Target sighted.
發現目標
You are my prey.
你就是我的獵物了
I-It's strong...
好強大…
But that's not all.
不僅如此
It's... enjoying the fight.
這傢伙還很樂在其中
A head-on battle against an opponent whose strength rivals your own!
與勢均力敵的對手正面交鋒
Rivals! Rivals! Rivals! Rivals!
勢均力敵…
Your core's a lot smaller than I thought.
沒想到你的核心這麼小啊
Got him!
太好了
-That's the vice-captain for you! -Not yet!
-不愧是副隊長 -還沒結束！
It got bigger?!
牠變巨大了？
Its fortitude is rising alongside the heat...
怪獸規模隨著放熱而上升
No way!
這是…
Fortitude...
怪獸規模…
9.0!
9.0！
EPISODE 10: SECRET REVEALED
（第10集：祕密曝光）
It's massive...
這也太巨大了
The vice-captain can't handle something that size by himself.
這已經不是副隊長能單獨解決的對手了
The vice-captain?
副隊長？
Hibino-san?
日比野？
Number Three: Return Slasher!
刀伐術3式，逆反襲
Your speed won't save you!
看你跑來跑去的
Incredible. He's still fighting it, even after it transformed. But...
真厲害，他配合怪獸的尺寸應變，可是…
My blades aren't cutting all the way through!
刀刃刺穿不了牠
This is why I hate Giant Kaiju!
所以我才這麼討厭大怪獸！
I'll just have to use my speed to get to the core in its back.
我得以速度取勝，一刀刺穿牠背後的核心
It's the only way.
除此之外別無他法
Exceeding operational limits.
已超過驅動極限
-Cancel maximum release immediately. -I'm overheating?
-請立即解除全解放狀態 -過熱了嗎？
It's been ten minutes since your maximum release!
戰力全解放已經超過十分鐘了
You have to shut it down!
再繼續下去會有危險！
So I'm down to one minute at best, huh?
看來我頂多只剩一分鐘了
It self-destructed?
自爆？
That's just like a Kaiju. Totally cold-blooded.
真符合沒血沒淚的冷血怪獸的作風
They're like living missiles! But...
簡直就像是個活體飛彈，不過…
It gave me a nice smoke screen.
也給了我一道不錯的煙幕
Number Six!
6式
Limit exceeded. Canceling maximum release.
已達到驅動極限，解除全解放狀態
Seek medical treatment immediately.
著裝者請立即進行治療
Vice-Captain...
副隊長
Vice-Captain!
副隊長！
Two hundred years ago, you would've been considered a genius.
如果是在江戶時代 你應該會被推崇為天才吧
But the era of blades has passed.
但是，刀的時代已經過去了
You understand that, right, Soshiro?
這點你也明白吧？宗四郎
Give up on joining the Defense Force.
你就放棄加入防衛隊吧
Vice-Captain! Vice-Captain!
副隊長！副隊長！
Vice-Captain!
副隊長！
Don't worry... I'm still alive.
別擔心，我還活著
I had my shields set to max... That Kaiju hits like a truck.
防護盾明明全開了 這隻怪獸真是不得了啊
I lost my maximum release.
全解放狀態也已經解除了
So what now?
接下來怎麼辦？
What can I do?
我能做什麼？
What's going on outside?
外部狀況如何？
The civilians are almost fully evacuated.
居民即將完成疏散
We're turning the tide against the Yoju, too.
對餘獸的戰況也漸入佳境
Yeah? Good stuff.
是嗎？那我就放心了
Guess I'd better keep fighting till the end, too.
那我也得堅持到最後一刻了
But you can't fight like that!
但你的身體會撐不住！
Hoshina-Style Sword-Slay Technique Number One: Air Slasher!
保科風格的刀伐術1式，虛影襲
You can't defeat me with those weapons.
你的那個武器打不倒我
You just figured that out? I knew it from the start!
少囉唆，這我早就知道了
Give up, Soshiro.
放棄吧，宗四郎
Your unleashed combat power with guns is low.
你的槍械解放戰力太低了
These days, that simply won't do.
在這個時代，刀已經不管用了
Give up, Hoshina-kun.
你放棄吧，保科
We're seeing more and more Giant Kaiju every year.
近年來，怪獸大型化的趨勢顯而易見
If all you can use is a blade, you'll get yourself killed out there.
如果你只使用刀，總有一天會喪命
People have been telling me that since I was a kid!
這些話我從小就聽到耳朵要長繭了
But she told me something else...
但是，她卻對我說…
Soshiro Hoshina, I'm told you're a blade specialist.
保科宗四郎，聽說你是用刀專家
Yes, that's right.
是的，沒錯
"Give up."
又要叫我放棄了
I need your help.
我需要你的力量
Will you join my division, Hoshina?
你願意加入我的部隊嗎？保科
We could easily find ourselves facing small but powerful foes someday.
今後仍有可能會出現強勁的小型怪獸
And I'm the opposite of you. I can't use a blade at all.
然而我跟你相反，對刀械一竅不通
I try not to even use kitchen knives.
甚至連菜刀都不想碰
When it's time for me to shoot my foe,
在我準備射穿敵人時
will you clear a path for me?
你能幫我開路嗎？
She left me in charge of the base.
她把基地託付給我了
I'll protect it if it kills me!
就算死，我也要守護這裡
Number Two: Cross Slasher!
2式，交叉襲
Number Three: Return Slasher!
3式，逆反襲
Number Four: Wild Slasher!
4式，亂襲
Number Five: Mist Slasher!
5式，幻霞襲
Number Six!
6式…
Vice-Captain!
副隊長！
I don't have a choice!
我別無選擇了
No...
不會吧？
If he transforms here, there really will be no escape!
要是在這種狀況下變身 就真的無法脫身了
No, Senpai!
不可以，前輩！
I'm sorry, Ichikawa.
抱歉，市川
My comrades' lives are more important!
隊友的生命無可取代！
Great work, everyone.
多虧你們撐到了現在
That voice...
這個聲音…
Hey, Kaiju.
怪獸
I win this fight.
我贏了
I'm the vice-captain of the base.
我是這個基地的副隊長
My job's to pass the baton to her.
我的職責就是交棒給她
Okonogi. This is an emergency, so I'm skipping the procedures.
小此木，由於狀況緊急 我就省略申請程序了
Yes, ma'am!
好的
Time to blow this thing up.
看我怎麼消滅牠
It's regenerating fast!
牠的再生速度很快
Captain, the core is in the back!
隊長，核心位於背部
Somewhere around the fourth to sixth thoracic vertebrae!
應該在第四胸椎至第六胸椎附近
Roger!
瞭解
Damn it!
可惡
I guess it's not that easy...
看來沒這麼簡單啊
Now, time to give it one more go...
那我就再拼鬥一下吧
Unleashed combat power, 63%.
解放戰力，63%
Number Four: Wild Slasher!
4式，亂襲
I'll limit its mobility to make it an easier target.
我要削減牠的機動力，製造攻擊機會
Number Two: Cross Slasher!
2式，交叉襲
This is crazy!
太亂來了
Your suit's already past its limit!
你的戰鬥服早就達到極限了！
It's regenerating...
牠再生了
My power output's too low. What do I do?
我的威力不夠了，怎麼辦？
Shinomiya?
四之宮？
Water Skimmer!
水切！
Damn it... I'm not even strong enough to scratch it yet?
可惡，現在的我根本無法對牠造成傷害
Keep going, Shinomiya.
繼續，四之宮
I'll cut open the shell, then you chop into the wounds!
我來斬裂甲殼，你朝著裂縫砍下去
It worked!
成功了
Shinomiya!
四之宮！
Overheated?
過熱了嗎？
That's fine, though.
這樣就夠了
You did well.
幹得好
Core exposed!
核心暴露在外了
You've got one bullet remaining, Captain!
隊長，還剩下一發子彈
Support the captain!
掩護隊長
Vice-Captain! Sorry we're late!
副隊長，抱歉我們來遲了
Don't give it time to regenerate, guys!
你們別讓牠有時間再生
Move.
動起來
Don't stop thinking!
別停止思考
Just five more seconds is enough...
再五秒就好
Come on, move!
動起來啊，我的身體！
Slice. Slice.
用刀斬開…
Slice open a path!
斬出一條道路！
That's the only way I have to leave my mark!
我只能用這種方式來證明自己了
Thank you, Hoshina.
謝謝你，保科
I was right to make you my vice-captain.
我真的很慶幸有你這個副隊長
Unleashed combat power, 96%.
戰力全解放，96%
Now it's time for me to shoot my foe.
現在換我來射穿牠了
You picked the wrong folks to mess with.
你找錯打架的對象了呢
T-The Honju is down!
擊敗主獸！
We did it.
我們成功了
Yeah.
嗯
Yes!
太好了
That's Captain Ashiro for you, huh?
真不愧是亞白隊長
I was right...
我的選擇果然沒錯
This is the Defense Force I've wanted to be in since I was a kid.
這就是我從小就想加入的防衛隊
They're all so cool...
這些人實在是太帥了
I want to stand right there with them someday...
總有一天，我也要跟他們站在一起
Your face is a mess.
話說回來，你的表情還真醜啊
What? How can you say that when I'm having an emotional moment?!
什麼啊！人家這麼感動 你這樣說太過分了吧
You've got a heart of stone!
冷酷無情的傢伙！
We're just getting started.
這只是剛開始而已
Let's do our best, too.
我們也好好加油吧
Yeah.
嗯
The captain and I will deal with the Yoju.
我跟隊長去殲滅餘獸…
No, you get some rest.
不，你給我去休息
You too, Captain.
隊長也該去休息喔
That's right. You only have 1% left until your suit overheats.
沒錯，隊長的戰鬥服 再1%就會達到驅動極限了
You fired a whole bunch of high-powered shots.
畢竟您連續進行了那麼強力的射擊
Leave the Yoju to us.
餘獸就交給我們吧
No, I'm fine.
不，我沒事
What is that?
那是什麼？
The Yoju...
餘獸…
So that last scream wasn't its death rattle?
所以剛才那並不是牠臨死前的吼叫聲？
Energy levels rising...
能量反應正在增大
It's an ultra-massive Yoju bomb!
這是超巨大的餘獸炸彈
The blast's estimated impact is equal to 20 kilotons of TNT!
推測爆炸威力相當於兩萬噸TNT炸藥
That's the same as a nuclear bomb!
這是核爆等級了吧
No! Don't shoot!
住手，別開槍
Evacuate!
全員撤退
No... there's no time...
不行，來不及了
If that thing hits the ground...
這東西要是掉下來…
Human...
人類…
Looks like this fight is a draw.
這場戰鬥，我們算是平手了呢
No, Senpai!
不可以，前輩！
Kafka?!
卡夫卡？
Get back here! There's nothing you can do!
回來！你去也於事無補！
Wait...
等等
How's he so fast?
這速度是怎麼回事？
That's not what 1% unleashed combat power looks like!
這不是解放戰力1%會有的動作
We're detecting a gigantic Kaiju signal above the base!
基地中央出現超巨大怪獸反應
Fortitude 9.8!
怪獸規模9.8
This signal, it's...
這個反應是…
Kaiju No. 8!
怪獸8號
I knew something was wrong...
我早就覺得不對勁了
But...
但是…
I found myself liking him so much...
我卻在不知不覺間開始賞識他
that I just turned a blind eye to the possibility.
所以才沒有正視這個可能性
You can have 1% of my expectations.
我對你抱有1%的期待
I'm sorry, Vice-Captain Hoshina.
對不起，保科副隊長
Fine.
我知道了啦
You did save my life, so I'll keep quiet about it for now.
看在你救了我的份上，我就暫時保密
I'm sorry, Kikoru.
對不起，琪歌露
You kept your promise and never told anyone...
明明你都幫我保守祕密了
And everyone else... I'm sorry for lying to you.
還有其他人也是，很抱歉瞞著大家
Just don't take any risks, please.
拜託你千萬別亂來
Sorry, Ichikawa. I think I'm gonna have to.
抱歉，市川，看來我無法遵守諾言了
You're a long way from being able to fight by my side.
想與我並肩作戰，你還差得遠了
Mina... I...
米娜，我…
Senpai!
前輩！
Do you have any idea what you're doing?
你知道自己在做什麼嗎？
Everyone else risked their lives during this fight!
隊上的大家都那麼奮力挺身作戰
I can't be the only one who puts his own safety first!
我怎麼可以只顧著自保！
I'm part of the Defense Force, too!
好歹我也是防衛隊
I'm an officer of the Third Division, too!
第3部隊的一員啊
So now it's my turn!
這次輪到我了！
Everyone, on the ground! Shields at max!
全員趴下，防護盾全開！
Well, now I've done it...
我搞砸了
My arms and legs are barely holding together...
我的雙手雙腳也快撐不住了
I'm too old to be pulling stunts like that.
都一把年紀了，還這麼亂來
Kafka Hibino...
日比野卡夫卡
No...
不對
Kaiju No. 8.
怪獸8號
I'm taking you into custody.
現在我要拘捕你